Dublin, Ireland | +353 8337 87229 | imcvarma@gmail.com | www.mahendra.design

# Mahendra Indukuri

#### ABOUT ME

Design graduate and cognitive science researcher with two years of experience working in UI/UX design roles. Expertise in developing interactive prototypes and style sheets using various tools like **Sketch, Adobe XD, Adobe CC and Zeplin**. My background in design, engineering and cognitive science help me tackle diverse problems in the domain of user experience and digital product design.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

#### **Tata Consultancy Services Ireland** – UX Designer

June 2021 - PRESENT, LETTERKENNY

Working on UI/UX Design for utility self-service portal and customer service representative UI for the UK market. Work includes UX Research, facilitating ideation workshops and UI prototyping.

#### Freelance Design — UI/UX Designer

SEPTEMBER 2020 - JUNE 2021, DUBLIN

- Working with startups and nonprofits as a UX Designer / Design consultant.
- Clients include <a href="https://www.hack-days.de/">https://progressive.international/</a> and multiple other organisations.

#### **Optum (UnitedHealth Group)** — UX Design Intern

JUNE 2020 - AUGUST 2020, DUBLIN

- "Exceeded Expectations" in contributions towards research, analysis and design according to end of term review.
- Conducted interviews and surveys to answer key questions relating to remote work and the future of work at Optum.
- Designed and tested an interface to address FOMO and disconnect that remote workers' experience.

#### **Silverlabs India (<u>rizzle.tv</u>)** – *UI/UX Designer*

FEBRUARY 2019 - JULY 2019, HYDERABAD

Worked on Rumbl (currently renamed Rizzle) application, Rumbl is a vlogging and social video creation app. It was conceived, designed and developed from scratch during my tenure at the organisation as the lead designer. (visit: rizzle.tv)

- Created user personas and analysed competing apps to find a market gap for a new photo/video mobile app.
- Conducted user interviews and created multiple iterations for A/B testing based on stakeholder feedback.
- Built wireframes, information architecture and task flow for multiple initial versions of the app.
- Created UI mockups including Iconography using Sketch/Adobe XD for both iOS and Android apps.
- Collaborated with UI devs to create micro-interactions, video player interactivity and animations in the app.
- Created Zeplin and additional documentation for UI devs regarding colour codes, aspect ratio, styling, resolutions.

## **WitCurve Tech.** – Product Designer

JULY 2018 - JANUARY 2019, HYDERABAD

WitCurve's products include web application that functions as an information management tool for K-12 educational institutions and a mobile application for parents and teachers for viewing performance-related data. (visit: witcurve.com)

• Translated research into wireframes and presented multiple iterations of low-fidelity mockups to stakeholders.

- Designed the UI/UX for Ionic 3 (hybrid iOS and Android app) based mobile application from scratch, deliverables
  included high fidelity mockups, style guides using Zeplin, Iconography and Information Architecture of the app.
- Designed UI for a web-based ERP tool based on Angular material framework, deliverables included iconography, high fidelity mockups, information architecture, documentation and animations for various micro-interactions.
- Developed front-end (HTML/CSS/AngularJS) for UI intensive data visualisation features.

## **Societe Generale Global Solutions Center** — UI/UX Design Intern

MAY 2017 - JULY 2017, BANGALORE

Worked on an application related to compliance in financial product trading.

- Designed a web-based application for viewing & editing FPML (Financial Product Markup Language).
- Designed and developed multiple data tables using Angular & material UI frameworks.

## **EDUCATION**

#### University College Dublin - MSc. Cognitive Science

SEPTEMBER 2019 - AUGUST 2020, DUBLIN.

Graduated from UCD with a masters degree in cognitive science focusing in psychology, philosophy of mind, computational modelling, neuropsychology and other contemporary approaches to cognitive science. Course work includes substantial first-hand research and literature research. Thesis project in the domain of human learning mentioned below.

### Indian Institute of Technology Guwahati — Bachelor of Design

JULY 2014 - MAY 2018, GUWAHATI.

Graduated from IIT Guwahati with a bachelor's degree in Design focusing on new media and interaction design. Coursework included project-based courses in graphic design, ergonomics, product design, interaction design and usability engineering.

## **ACHIEVEMENTS**

#### **NovaUCD Student Enterprise Competition** — *Individual Cash Prize of* €1000

MAY 2020 - JUNE 2020, DUBLIN

Individually won a cash prize of €1000 from NovaUCD for being selected into the NovaUCD Student Enterprise Competition after a successful pitch. Worked on Ideation, Design and development of a business plan for a digital tool that helps people grow in their career. Media article related to the competition can be found here:

https://www.siliconrepublic.com/start-ups/ucd-student-startups-novaucd-enterprise

#### **Dogpatch Labs Hackathon** – 2nd Place

SEPTEMBER 2020

Helped our team secure second place and win a cash prize of €1250 in a highly competitive fintech hackathon with contributions towards design, prototyping and final pitching.

## **ACADEMIC PROJECTS**

## Storytelling in Virtual Reality — Media Lab, Indian Institute of Technology Guwahati

Worked on Virtual Reality (VR) and the future of storytelling in VR, explored concepts such as hypermontage and gaze-based interactivity through an interactive prototype for google cardboard developed using unity.